import { Trivia } from 'src/app/models/util-types';

export const trivias: Partial<Trivia>[] = [
  {
    question: 'What is the name of Han Solo’s ship?',
    answer: 'Millennium Falcon'
  },
  {
    question:
      'The young Jedi Knight, Anakin Skywalker, becomes who in Star Wars?',
    answer: 'Darth Vader'
  },
  {
    question: 'The planet Kashyyyk is home to who?',
    answer: 'Chewbacca and the Wookiees'
  },
  {
    question:
      'In Revenge of the Sith and Attack of the Clones, what color is Yoda’s lightsaber?',
    answer: 'Green'
  },
  {
    question: 'The X-wing fighter has how many engines?',
    answer: 'Four'
  },
  {
    question: 'Jedi Council consists of how many members?',
    answer: '12'
  },
  {
    question: 'What were Luke’s aunt and uncle’s jobs on Tatooine?',
    answer: 'Moisture farmers'
  },
  {
    question: 'How many languages is C-3P0 fluent in?',
    answer: 'Over 6 million'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which character is partially named after George Lucas’ son?',
    answer: 'Dexter Jettster'
  },
  {
    question:
      'How many Dewbacks were in the original 1977 theatrical cut of the first Star Wars movies?',
    answer: 'Two'
  },
  {
    question: 'What color is Mace Windu’s lightsaber?',
    answer: 'Purple'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who played the part of Mace Windu?',
    answer: 'Samuel L. Jackson'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which species stole the plans to the death star?',
    answer: 'Bothans'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What kind of trooper is introduced at the beginning of Rogue One?',
    answer: 'Death Troopers'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who kissed Leia first, Han or Luke?',
    answer: 'Luke'
  },
  {
    question: 'What does AT-AT stand for?',
    answer: 'All Terrain Armored Transport'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What odds does C-3P0 give Han for successfully navigating the asteroid field?',
    answer: '3,720 to 1'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who are the masters of the Dark Side that want to rule the galaxy?',
    answer: 'The Sith'
  },
  {
    question: 'Count Dooku is also known as who?',
    answer: 'Darth Tyranus'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the name of Boba Fett’s ship?',
    answer: 'Slave 1'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the original commander of the Death Star?',
    answer: 'Grand Moff Tarkin'
  },
  {
    question: 'What was the name of the planet that the clones were made on?',
    answer: 'Kamino'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the largest annual podrace in the world?',
    answer: 'The Boonta Eve Classic'
  },
  {
    question:
      'When Leia first tells Han Solo that she loves him, what is his reply?',
    answer: '“I know.”'
  },
  {
    question: 'What day is Wookiee Life Day?',
    answer: 'November 17th'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Peter Mayhew played the part of who in the original Star Wars Trilogy?',
    answer: 'Chewbacca'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What language are the words written on Darth Vader’s chest piece in?',
    answer: 'Ancient Hebrew'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the other name for The Imperial Probe Droid?',
    answer: 'Probot'
  },
  {
    question:
      'The four Jedi Masters Kit Fisto, Mace Windu, Agen Kolar, and Saesee Tinn, were killed by who?',
    answer: 'Darth Sidious'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Where was Luke Skywalker originally headed to pick up power converters?',
    answer: 'Tosche Station'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which two sectors does The Empire Strikes Back take place in?',
    answer: 'The Sluis Sector and The Anoat Sector'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who’s the only rebel pilot to survive all three movies in the original trilogy?',
    answer: 'Wedge Antilles'
  },
  {
    question: 'What species is Yoda?',
    answer: 'It is unknown'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of the imperial admiral at the beginning of The Empire Strikes Back?',
    answer: 'Ozzeo'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the name of the Toydarian who owned Anakin Skywalker?',
    answer: 'Watto'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who was the last one to jump down the Death Star’s garbage chute?',
    answer: 'Han'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What race of aquatic sentient beings does Jar-Jar Binks belong to?',
    answer: 'The Gungans, a species that lives on Naboo'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who killed Han Solo?',
    answer: 'His son, Kylo Ren'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who built C-3P0?',
    answer: 'Anakin Skywalker'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of the organization that builds a blockade around Naboo?',
    answer: 'The Trade Federation'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which actress starred as Queen Amidala’s decoy and hand-maiden Sabè?',
    answer: 'Kiera Knightley'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What creature lives in the garbage compactor of the original Death Star?',
    answer: 'Dianoga'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What planet does Obi-Wan Kenobi travel to where he discovers an army of clones created for the Republic?',
    answer: 'Kamino'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who is the Sith leader of the Separatist movement?',
    answer: 'Count Dooku'
  },
  {
    question: 'What does the Emperor say is Luke’s weakness?',
    answer: 'His faith in his friends'
  },
  {
    question: 'How many arms does the alien diner owner, Dex Jettster, have?',
    answer: 'Four'
  },
  {
    question: 'What do Han and Luke ride on in the snow on Hoth?',
    answer: 'Tauntaun'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who is Jango Fett’s son?',
    answer: 'Boba Fett'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which arm of Anakin’s does Count Dooku cut off?',
    answer: 'The right'
  },
  {
    question:
      'When Luke asked what was in the cave on Dagobah, what was Yoda’s response?',
    answer: '“Only what you take with you.”'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is Chancellor Palpatine’s malicious Sith alter-ego?',
    answer: 'Darth Sidious'
  },
  {
    question:
      'In what “detention block” was Princess Leia being held in, in the first Death Star?',
    answer: 'AA-23'
  },
  {
    question: 'What does “TIE” stand for in TIE Fighter?',
    answer: 'Twin Ion Engines'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who is the senator that adopts Leia, and what planet is he from?',
    answer: 'Senator Bail Organa, from Alderaan'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which Wookiee Jedi Master was renowned for his ability to sense the future?',
    answer: 'Tyvokka'
  },
  {
    question: '“You were right,” were whose last words to Luke?',
    answer: 'Darth Vader’s'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of the order Darth Sidious gives the clone troopers, which means they will kill all Jedi?',
    answer: 'Order 66'
  },
  {
    question: 'What was the nickname of Snoova, the Wookiee bounty hunter?',
    answer: 'Madclaw'
  },
  {
    question:
      'In the Star Wars Holiday Special, which ocean planet was introduced?',
    answer: 'Panna'
  },
  {
    question:
      'How many people does Darth Vader kill in The Empire Strikes Back?',
    answer: 'Two'
  },
  {
    question:
      'In The Empire Strikes Back, name the two people Darth Vader kills.',
    answer: 'Admiral Ozzel and Captain Needa'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What’s the name of the planet where Anakin Skywalker loses the duel against Obi-Wan, which leaves him mangled and burned?',
    answer: 'Mustafar'
  },
  {
    question: 'What do they call the children being trained as Jedi?',
    answer: 'Younglings'
  },
  {
    question: 'What bounty hunter used a bowcaster as his weapon of choice?',
    answer: 'Embo'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What can be considered the primary reason for Anakin falling to the dark side?',
    answer: 'He wanted to save Padmè from death during childbirth'
  },
  {
    question: 'On what planet did Cadbane capture Bolla Ropal?',
    answer: 'Devaron'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the Rule of 2?',
    answer: 'There can only be two Sith Lords at one time'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the composer for every film in the Star Wars Saga?',
    answer: 'John Williams'
  },
  {
    question: 'What are the short junk-collecting aliens on Tatooine called?',
    answer: 'Jawas'
  },
  {
    question: 'What are Luke’s aunt and uncle called?',
    answer: 'Owen and Beru Lars'
  },
  {
    question: 'Where were Luke and Leia born?',
    answer: 'Polis Massa'
  },
  {
    question:
      'How big is the exhaust port that is the target for Rebel Alliance Starfighters in A New Hope?',
    answer: 'Two meters'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which planet holds the hidden rebel base?',
    answer: 'Yavin IV'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What planet does the Rebel Alliance find refuge on at the beginning of The Empire Strikes Back?',
    answer: 'Hoth'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who is Han’s friend who runs the cloud city of Bespin?',
    answer: 'Lando Calrissian'
  },
  {
    question:
      'In what substance is Han Solo frozen for delivery to Jabba the Hutt?',
    answer: 'Carbonite'
  },
  {
    question: 'What race of alien is Admiral Ackbar?',
    answer: 'Mon Calamari'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which year was the film Return of the Jedi released?',
    answer: '1983'
  },
  {
    question: 'How old is Yoda when he dies?',
    answer: ' 900'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of the Emporer’s Hand who was on Jabba’s sail barge during Han’s rescue?',
    answer: 'Mara Jade'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What planet is the second Death Star orbiting in Return of the Jedi?',
    answer: 'The forest moon of Endor'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who infiltrates Jabba’s palace in disguise to save Han Solo?',
    answer: 'Princess Leia'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What are the miniature aliens that help the Rebels destroy the shield generator on Endor?',
    answer: 'Ewoks'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who stars as Han Solo in the original Star Wars films?',
    answer: 'Harrison Ford'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What makes Han Solo temporarily blind after he is freed from the carbonite?',
    answer: 'Hibernation sickness'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of Lando Calrissian’s co-pilot in Return of the Jedi?',
    answer: 'Nien Nunb'
  },
  {
    question: 'George Lucas’ original last name for Luke was what?',
    answer: 'Starkiller'
  },
  {
    question: 'Han Solo’s trusty blaster is what type of blaster?',
    answer: 'DL-44'
  },
  {
    question: 'How tall is Chewbacca?',
    answer: '7’6″'
  },
  {
    question: 'What planet does Rey live on in The Force Awakens?',
    answer: 'Jakku'
  },
  {
    question: 'Luke Skywalker’s self-imposed exile takes place on what planet?',
    answer: 'Ach-TO'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is Poe Dameron’s droid called?',
    answer: 'BB-8'
  },
  {
    question: 'On which planet does the Resistance have its base?',
    answer: 'D’Qar'
  },
  {
    question: 'How old was Padmè when she became Queen?',
    answer: '14'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who are Kylo Ren’s father and mother?',
    answer: 'Han Solo and Leia Organa'
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who is the cantina owner on Takodana who has a lightsaber in her possession?',
    answer: 'Maz Katana'
  },
  {
    question: 'Who is the supreme leader of the First Order?',
    answer: 'Snoke'
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of Luke’s childhood best friend that later served beside him in the rebellion?',
    answer: 'Biggs Darklighter'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the red substance found on the planet Crait?',
    answer: 'Salt'
  }
];
